MOHAMED MAHMOUD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+358 44 208 0939

madel413@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mohamed-capo

Helsinki, Finland

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, other framwoks

JavaScript, TypeScript, React

SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Node.js, Express

REST, GraphQL, Postman, Apollo

AWS and A little of Python

EDUCATION

Encoder training Angular and .Net

Business College Helsinki

08/2020 - Present

I have completed the coding part and what is left is the theoretical part

Business management

Higher Institute for Cooperative and administrative Studies Egypt, Cairo

06/2003 - 06/2007

LANGUAGES

Arabic, mother tongue

English, excellent

Finnish, professional working

PROFILE

Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success. Respectful self-motivator gifted at finding reliable solutions for software issues. I have an experience in Frontend and Backend and offering skills in React and TypeScript. Hardworking and passionate job seeker with strong organizational. Ready to help team achieve company goals

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer

Nordcloud IBM Company, Helsinki

09/2022 - 02/2023

- Designed reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve user experience

Full Stack Developer Trainee

Integrify

04/2022 - 08/2022

- Assisted with creating cross-platform UI web components and built responsive applications using front-end frameworks.
- Worked with senior developer to implement web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, MongoDB and PostgreSQL
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- Develop, code, modify and debug application programs

The restaurateur, an entrepreneur

Capo33

09/2019 - 04/2020

- Food preparation and monitored safety protocols. Implemented effective inventory control systems to reduce food spoilage and waste.
- Implemented effective inventory control systems to reduce food spoilage and waste.
- Enhanced financial controls to minimize theft and loss risks, continuously maintaining accurate accounts and cash drawers.

COMPETENCIES

Software development

Web authentication

API design knowledge

